hello welcome to another edition of club
shay shea i am your host i'm also the
proprietor of club shayche and i
promised you when we started this
podcast
that i would bring you some of the
biggest and brightest stars and athletes
in their particular genres
and today i have one uh he's a comedian
he's an actor he's an executive producer
and he's the fastest actor to make the
elite hollywood club
the 20 million dollar club my dog
chris tucker all my life been grinding
all my life
sacrifice hustle pay the price wanna
slice
got to roll the dice that's why all my
life i've been grinding all my life
all my life been running all my life
sacrifice
plus will pay the price
[Music]
ain't got none of that money no more i
don't want nobody calling me
how you been doing bro man i'm doing
good man i'm doing great i'm doing great
how are you
bro i'm good i really can't complain i'm
gainfully employed
i'm doing better than a lot of people
you know the 2020 was bad for a lot of
people
a lot of people lost their jobs a lot of
people a lot of family lost loved ones
but i was very fortunate and i'm blessed
so yes
yes man it was it was a year man but
we're going to get through it man i
remember i was in new york for 9 11.
and i thought the world was ending
because it was the night after it was
the morning after michael jackson had
the big concerts
in new york uh the 9th and the 10th
right next day was 9 11.
woke up man people call me you know they
we getting attacked and all this stuff
i i said now we're about to end i just
laid back down
and man and then some friends call us to
get up man we getting on the bus we're
going up to jersey
and man you know the world started back
up and we got past that we're gonna get
past this pandemic man and
i've been taking advantage of these last
uh 10 11 months and
been focusing been organizing been
praying
and it took a phenomenon to get get me
to get organized but uh but
god made it happen so sin
you mentioned the pandemic so what have
you actually been up to
man you know what i've been resting you
know cause i was touring i was touring
and i was going you know get home and
then get back on the plane which i love
to do and you know i started out doing
stand-up comedy but i've been resting
organizing praying uh meditating and
focusing there
i took advantage of this time like i
said you know i knew i know we're gonna
get out of this
right but you know so i wasn't gonna be
lazy and not do nothing
gotta organize got my rest uh you know
of course worked a lot on you know
stand-up stuff scripts and and producing
stuff
but mainly uh you know prayer life and
resting and just getting that together
man and that's been good for me because
i'm ready to go now
i'm ready to go we get out of this i
don't know how many people know this
about you but i know this about you
because i know you're a little better
than most people
you're an avid golfer how's the golf
game coming
man it's coming good i finally got a
coach because everybody say get a
teacher you know because you know
we grew up playing basketball and and
baseball and football you teach yourself
you know black people you can't teach
yourself
in golf you got to get a teacher and i
got a coach
and he's helping me tell me to turn the
left hip turn the left heel i'm saying
no i'm gonna swing it no no
it's all about the left hip so i'm
getting better and i'm almost getting
ready to beat my brother them so it's
going good
so my brother always comes to your
tournament you have it every year i
don't know if you're gonna have it this
year
and he always tells me i'm going to talk
i'm going to tucker's tournament
can you beat him no man i talked to
marcus allen about your brother
yesterday i said marcus i heard you're a
stretch golfer he said that that's good
for y'all to say that but that ain't
true
i said what about what about uh sterling
he said sterling is a stretch call he's
better than a strategy golfer i said i
don't even know what that means
he said he's a plus plus plus plus
something i said what
and sterling told me i played the only
trophy i got from winning golf is in my
room we played at uh
lake uh uh lake what's the big famous
one here
uh easily here in atlanta georgia tiger
won the big championship right
i played on your brother team on
sterling team and we won
sterling's so cold blood he didn't get
his trophy he just left before they gave
the trophy he said i wanted to thank him
and hug him against him he was gone on
the road drive because you know we
talked about he drive everywhere
i said man it's the only joke i got and
it's a bad trophy
it's beautiful that warren a work done
tournament man
that's the only trophy i ever won
besides my own golf tournament
they gave me a free honorary trophy so
he's good though man so you say you're
getting better let me ask you this
can you beat charles barkley i could
beat charles brockley now the way he
used to swing he got a little bit better
i could beat y'all barkley my somebody
just asked me that
last night they were laughing when they
were saying can you play better job i
said yeah i could beat y'all
he came to my tournament last year too
but y'all that's my boy but i could be
and i'm gonna be able to beat him once i
get these lessons done
well i mean it seems to be like the golf
is the new thing because i see a lot of
athletes like when they retire football
players basketball baseball hockey and
forget the
professional sport that golf uh is the
sport that they choose
what is it about golf that you thinks
attract ex-athletes
and even guys like yourself because it's
always a task
man it's it's you never figure it out
it's always another level of the game
once you get the driving right hitting
it off the tee you got to work on your
irons you got to get that right and then
you when you get close to the green you
got to get the putt the chipping and the
putting right
so it's always a task and it's always
you're trying to figure it out you're
thinking the whole time
and then the fellowship when you're on
the course with your
your brothers or buddies and stuff you
know you get to know somebody in four
hours they're gonna let you know who
they are for real you can be like oh
man ain't even though you talk like that
or you'll be like oh you're pretty smart
oh man that's the last time i'm playing
with you you know so you're gonna know
something about your
people with after four hours of playing
go and then you knock the ball in the
woods
you get to experience nature and i'm
always in the woods and
one time i was talking to a deer one
time did you see my ball
he said it was over there but you know
i'm a country boy i grew up like creeks
and stuff like that so i love the woods
being out in nature so it's all that
good stuff with golf
who would be your ideal foursome
idea for them i would say uh michael
jordan
michael jordan you your brother
and tiger woods i'm gonna have a lot of
people out there
who who's the one person you would like
to play with
that you said i beat him
oh well my brother my brother cause he's
been beating me
lately and uh i've been and i'm getting
better because i got my lessons so what
i just want to keep continually
to get him and uh but we have a lot of
fun with it i don't even want to get too
serious that i don't
i don't have fun with it because then
i'll be like you know all on another
level with that yet
but a lot of people take it real serious
though they take it i mean they take it
seriously
yeah yeah but but my brother honestly i
would like to beat michael jordan
i want to go to his course his own
course and beat him
and then talk about him in front of
everybody just if people work for them
and everybody
i would love to do that because michael
is the type of guy if he beats you
if he's beating you or beats you in
anything he'll never let you forget it
he's literally talking while the event
while it's going on
we can't get worse michael talked junk
man
i mean i went to his party to honor him
and he told my girlfriend what'd you do
with him
i looked at him i said he said oh that's
okay cause i like him i actually like
him
and i agree with him that's how famous
he is he do like me baby
i saw you i saw a picture the other day
and this gentleman just classed recently
on the golf course you and deebo
talk about your relationship with deebo
and what he meant
in his past what what a great guy man
i've known devo known me since i was a
little like a young
teenager going to the comedy clubs he
used to come to atlanta and scare
everybody out of the comedy club he'd
come in there just yelling and screaming
skeleton scanned the comedians
you didn't know if he was for real or
not so i've known him for a long time
and then we end up doing fridays
together
and man he just made that movie uh work
man he
him and everybody else man made that
movie a classic that was my one of my
first
co-starring roles and man he's always
going to be uh etched
in in my story because uh we've done a
lot of movie we did fifth element
together movie called fifth element we
did a jackie brown i did a cameo in that
and and the last year he came to my golf
tournament last year
came to church with us after the
tournament the next morning
just a good christian brother i did
something in los angeles in l.a with him
last year
or the year before last and man it just
seemed like last year the year before
last he was around we were around each
other a lot
and i was uh like man this is cool i
bumped into him at marcus allen's golf
tournament
and uh i said what's up man and then we
kept you know got it kept in touch and
we just was bumping into each other
everywhere man and uh and then doing
stuff together so i thank god that i had
to
spend some good time with him before he
passed man good brother
he was a great brother he's a great guy
and even take a joke
i remember in 90 with the super bowl in
atlanta the first super bowl in atlanta
i met him in the hotel and he walked up
to me we started talking to carrying on
conversation he's like what you doing
like i don't know i don't know
he's like well hey well let's kick it
tonight so we you know he and i if he
and i
and we're going although we're going to
different places and i re and he
i didn't really you know i was like okay
you know he has one green eye
and a brown eye yeah yeah i'm gonna see
you know
so we joking and he's backing up i was
like bro
look over the other shoulder because if
you look at that you're going to call us
somebody he like man look here man i
know for your jokes
but he started laughing and we started
we kept a relationship going
but yeah he's just a great guy
he really he really was man just a good
good good hearted person
good christian brother man and we're
gonna miss him man we're gonna meet some
good guy man
let's let's talk about let's talk about
friday that was
really your first that was your breakout
role i mean you were you know you were a
comedian and a lot of people knew you
but that was the role that put chris
tucker on the map
how much of that did you get to ad-lib
and how much of it was scripted that
you're like nah i need to do it like
this in order to make it
me yeah a lot of it man a lot of it
because uh you know i knew i had to make
it special i had to
to you know uh spend some time to
develop the character
you know so i can make it you know make
it interesting and uh
make an impact man but when i got the
script it was like 60 pages
uh but they were writing at the writing
at the same time and about time we got
on the set it was it was done
the script was done but but but the
director gave me free range
and ice cube gave me free range to come
up with stuff on the set because they
knew i came from stand up and you know
i'm in the moment a lot and i come up
with stuff
so man a lot of it was was uh was in the
moment stuff
and it was because you know it was just
a great environment great
great actors man like i said tiny was
just great when he came up on that
screen
we really was scared i was scared i was
like whoa whoa i didn't remember this
part of the script
and i was like uh you know tucking my
stuff in he really that he really made
me act for good and cute
of course was cube and uh you know all
everybody in that movie made that movie
work man and i'm just happy blessed to
be a part of it have been a part of it
did you know it was gonna be what it
became did you think in the moment when
you're doing that movie you're like
this is it this is gonna be a
blockbuster did you know
no i didn't know but i knew i was
prepared because i got up man i got in
the mirror i said i'm gonna i'm
this is my shot it wasn't about money it
wasn't about it was about the
opportunity
and i try to tap into that uh now you
know at this point in my career
it was just about the opportunity and i
said this is my shot i got to be ready
when
i got it on my lines and when i'm on
that set whatever comes
for me i'm gonna be ready for i'm not
gonna let not one moment go past me
funny moment
or whatever reaction and i was i know i
was prepared and i said if i'm prepared
and you know i i didn't know i knew good
things could happen
from that you know that's all i knew i
was prepared i was ready
but did you know by playing that role
so well there could never be another
smokey other than you
that's not a role that someone else
could play that's not a role that
someone else can do no matter how many
fridays
there could never be another smoky did
you know you had put together that type
of performance
i did not know i had no clue i knew that
that uh it was felt good and it was
working and
and i was in the because when you're in
the moment you don't you don't know what
you're doing you just like
it's just work you know you're just
feeling good about it and stuff coming
out of you it's like god takes over
it and you just going and that's all i
knew that i i was ready
and i was excited about it and uh
because that you know i wanted to i was
auditioning for tv shows because i was
on the road so much i was ready to get
off the road
and get into movies and get a bigger
audience because i was going to see
you have to see the same cities you know
in the same year
you know i was making a living but i was
like i got to move to the next level and
i was back then i was just so sensitive
to that i knew i was like this is the
time to be on tv or movies
and i always wanted to do movies and i
got it got fridays when i came out of
auditioning for another movie i was up
against d.l hewley
d.l got the part on tv but when i was
walking out my manager's assistant said
but you got fridays uh we just found out
you got fridays we don't know if you got
this yet
but i know uh all i knew was i was
prepared so i try to always be prepared
for stuff
you go back and we look at friday we
look at some of the comedians that were
in friday
bernie mac was the pastor john
witherspoon was pops
what was it like working with those guys
on the set
oh my god bernie ray was also in that
movie oh yeah ronaldo ray oh man it was
just
one of that was the highlights for me
working with bernie and
and mr witherspoon john was well i told
the director i said i gotta have a scene
with with mr witherspoon john
witherspoon got to have a scene he said
all right we'll write something in all
right
every day i was bugging him like what
what what what scene now cause this is
gonna be forever
and this is this man is a legend he said
i got the scene you're gonna go up to
him and you're gonna tell me you gotta
use the rad bathroom he gonna slam the
door on you i said
that's all i need i just want that
moment he gave it to me
bernie i was just always a big fan of
his
i never seen somebody tell up a room a
comedy
theater like bernie mac man i went to
the wilton in atlanta and i got a school
i got a schooling
i got a lesson from bernie bernie told
the room up man it was like
the holy ghost was in there man it was
like church it was like a picnic
it was like a family reunion i never
seen anything like that so he's always
been one of my favorite comedians him
robin harris richard fryer
you know eddie murphy those guys bill
cosby all those guys been some of my
greatest
favorite one of my favorite scenes is
when bernie mac comes up he's the pastor
and uh you and you y'all were smoking on
the porch
and he said he needed a little support
glaucoma and he was talking about at the
church
on oh what was it uh he said somebody's
church is about this [__]
they share and you said about normandy
and west and well
yeah yeah the twitter twin twin
yeah so
that was all in the moment was that in
the script or did you add live that part
i had live it i have lived it man cause
one thing about when the camera stopped
we still was having fun it was like you
got bernie mac on the set
with me and john witherspoon and
uh ice cube we were still having fun you
know at ice cube you know
i grew up listening to his music so it
was like i was fascinated you know
sitting next to him
so we talking about stories and stuff so
we was we was just having fun man i was
in a good mood and we was like coming up
with stuff every two seconds
you know even when we went filming it
was a lot of that stuff was great
you do the movie it's a success
beyond success beyond success beyond
successful
did you do such a great job you priced
yourself
out of the sequel or did you not want to
come back or did you want to move on to
say i did that
i'm done with that i want to go to
something else i wanted to move on
because when i when i did something i
never i never wanted to do it again
i was like uh back then i was all about
going to the next level
i like i said i had a good sense of like
okay now it's time to go do an
action movie uh whatever it is you know
so well when you asked me to do a
fridays i was like
nah nah i want to go through something
else we don't did that you know what cuz
studios think about the money and then
uh
news is like oh we can make some money
with this i was thinking about my career
saying no
i want to go do money talks or something
let me do my home movie with charlie
sheen
i did that movie instead that was uh
everybody talks oh thank you man thank
you we had some fun
jolly is my boy man he's still my boy
but yeah it was all
it was for me it was about going to the
next level keep keep uh you know going
to the next seven they
couldn't believe i didn't want to do
another one but i was just and i was
right when i think back on it i was like
this is time to do something do we did
that and i did everything i can do when
i was prepared and i'm satisfied with it
let's go to the next one do you believe
had you done a second
friday that would have people would have
looked at you and said that's the only
type of movies he can do
i think it uh would have would have
probably been managed diminish the first
one because
sometimes you can't get something out of
certain movies you can't get nothing
else out of it
but they were able to do it with
friday's two and three they figured out
a way to do it
but uh i just was where i was and i
think it's the right way
uh to do it was at that time and uh
not to not to go back on it because you
know then it became a classic and um so
you know i i didn't you know i didn't i
didn't mess with i'm glad i didn't mess
with but something like you know the
rush hour movies
action movies it's a little bit more
easier to do one two
and three and then they offered me 25
million i said you know what let's let's
get off your morals for a minute and go
ahead
no no no it was it made sense because i
knew that we could do something else
with it and it was a
you know it was what it was you know the
rush hours and stuff can you believe
of all the things that you've
accomplished that people still go back
and they talk about friday and they
quote you from friday
and they do all these things can you
believe the staying power
that you had in that movie no man i
you know i never you know sometimes when
god bless you man you he bless you more
than what you can even dream and that's
one of those things because
it was just a small movie we filmed it
in 20 days and i didn't get
you know about ten thousand dollars
forward or whatever i didn't care i just
was i wanted the opportunity
uh but i can't believe uh how about i
talk about back up
how much you got i got about ten
thousand dollars because the movie
calls they took well they got different
stories but it was either two million or
three million to do we only i know we
had 20 days because directed and
reminded me every day we got 20 days man
because you better not mess up we only
have two takes we can only take two
takes that mean you know i can only do
my lines
twice if i mess up one time you get one
more time and that's it we're going to
cut your part
so i knew we when we was on the street
one street the whole time and then we
went some stuff in the studio little
scenes in the studio like bedrooms
things like that
but we it was it was that small of a
movie but
that was the beauty of it because it
allowed me to get into the character it
wasn't no big distractions like big
big movie sets you got like people and
sound people oh everybody want to be a
star but that movie was just a camera
and me and cube on on on the um porch
and you know and then you know magic
came out of it you know
thank god and now with the advent of the
internet you see all the smoky
impersonations you see all this you got
knocked
out you see the uh you know
you see everybody on you doing this
gabrielle union and d
wade reenacted one of your scenes oh
oh yeah yeah they did they did an
unbelievable job
oh i'm getting that i gotta see that i
gotta see that
so i look at you and when you had the
part with a uh
phase i love big big worm i mean big
purr yeah
that would i mean that was some some
great
acting i mean it was just like thank you
how did
how were you able to do because you went
from like you smoking extra cue
smoking do it with bernie mac smoking
talking to pop smokey talking to
accused mom to now all of a sudden it's
you and
you leaning in the car and you're trying
to uh uh shy somebody's money
you know how how did you go from this
this because like you said you only had
20 days to shoot this entire movie yeah
yeah well the beauty about the scene
with me and big worm with faison love we
were best friends
so we clowned around all day every day
you know going to the comedy clubs at
night every night going to different
kinds of performing
we clown around every day so it was so
easy to work with him but
we were laughing a lot faison would
laugh all the time because he looking at
me like
look at him try to be serious and
because i had to stay in character
i would make him laugh off camera
because he was making me laugh so it was
so easy because we were friends and to
get that
that stuff good and then bernie mac of
course you know he's one of
my heroes fan i was a fan of him so
everybody
everybody i had a connection with
watching john witherspoon and um
uh you know watching eq growing up with
his music so everybody it was just
every time i was with him i was excited
and it was uh it was just easy to do
it was easy how did you come up with the
line when
the late the girl that cue neil lone's
character you had a crush on her
and she said she has a friend that she
want to hook you up with
yeah if you said she kind of looked like
janet jackson yeah
okay so how did you come up with that
part was that written in or did you add
lil
janet jackson more like freddie jackson
well that was written in that that part
was written
but on the phone when i got on the phone
with her like yeah you know what debbie
lived right
oh that was just me saying uh okay i'm
on the phone with somebody nobody was on
the other line
and i'm like okay i got control that was
all me
and uh jackson
jackson that's all me and then and then
i auditioned
on the part of of the girl when i walked
up to the girl
and i found out she wasn't what i
thought she was that's how i got fried
is because i was like
yeah i know you're hungry you know my
mama don't like a lot of people with me
when i pick them up
no oh and then she take the wig off damn
all that was how i got the part i i just
made that up in the room and they wrote
it down when i was auditioning
give me your top five hood classics of
all time
a new jack city new jack city i like new
jack city
boys in the hood boys in the hood the
mac
mac and i'm going well you took my hood
hood classics ugh because i always say
scarface is aggressive to me
because i love scuffy we grew up we
accidentally saw that in matinee when we
were kids my mom and dad didn't know
what we was watching we was gone they
sent us to the movie and i said
whoa this is acting i thought i was in
you know
a whole big old drug world with that but
uh the other one
could be off hand maybe minister society
oh
uptown saturday night uptown saturday
night
let's do it again those are in there you
ain't gonna put
you're not gonna put friday in their
house oh yeah yeah you
any of them without friday being in it
thank you man good look at that big bro
you that's right
that's right you grew up in atlanta what
was it growing up in atlanta
during the time and what did you want to
be what when you were growing up
you know i was blessed man i found out
early you know uh
that i i like entertainment you know
going to the movies seeing uh stir crazy
with richard pryor in it
and gene gene wilder proud walking down
the prison come on we bad
we bad i was just fascinated when when
when richard pryor came on the scene
eddie murphy in 48 hours you know
he was in the prison like cash case you
know it i was like yeah go eddie you
know
so i and then i when i go when i went to
school
uh you know i'm the youngest of six kids
so
i had a lot i watched a lot i i observed
a lot because
you know you can't say that you're the
youngest and all you got three older
brothers
two sisters they say shut up or just
what you know so i just watched them
i i you know it was and i watched them
make mistakes you know they did
they get a whooping i'll be like what
they do i don't i don't want to get a
weapon when i get older like that what
happened i ain't take out the guy
because
i'm gonna make sure i take out the
garbage when it's my turn shoot daddy
good god so i learned a lot at a young
age and then i you know that
you know it was just comedy all around
us cause you know a big family
there's always something people trying
to get in the bathroom get out of the
bathroom girl
we trying to go to school mama shut up
what y'all mean i don't know
so it was always something going on a
house and it just i was just around
funny stuff and i didn't even know it
and i was funny i guess too
and went to school and people said man
you're funny and you're like eddie
murphy or something i'm like what you
talking about then you know i don't
dress up for pee
i will preach to the whole everybody who
didn't dress out in the bleachers
i'm like all right get your books your
bibles out that i would make them laugh
for about 30 minutes
even a teacher come over there and be
like what is going this food
and then they say you need to host the
talent show cause you you got something
i said well how much they paying are
they paying anything
and uh do they you get some good grades
or something no you just go
so i got like 30 to 30 dollars to host a
talent show
y'all told my first joke they laughed i
said this is
it this is what i'm gonna do because you
know school wasn't easy for me you know
so i said
i ain't going to college i barely got
out of high school i'm gonna finish this
right now
i'm lucky i got out of here so yeah you
went to columbia
which is in decatur right yeah decatur
in georgia yeah all right and decatur
decatur now y'all had some athletes that
was that track uh gwen torrance went to
uh decatur
with the columbia yeah i i don't you
know i know i know a little bit of
they had awesome track uh track program
off the chain
that's right that's right she graduated
with my brother or sister older sister
so what was sport i mean you went to a
school that was very that that had good
high school athletic program you never
wanted to play sports
i did play sports i wanted to go pro
like you but
i bought both of my wrists and practice
that was it
that was that was god saying you better
go figure something out i jumped up
man to catch a ball or two you know just
to catch if we just throwing
getting ready for france i jumped up and
instead of coming down on my butt ball
i said oh my brace myself broke both of
my wrists
and even the doctors was laughing like
how did you do this i said man just take
me to the doctor
take the hospital and that's when i quit
i said i said i need to do something
else but
yeah man i love sports and you know
wanted want to be go
pro like everybody else but you realize
at a very young age
so doing the comedic thing when you were
in high school or coming up
was it to make people laugh or to make
make sure people weren't laughing at you
because i have a funny side but i used
to talk with a lisp
and i what i found at a very young age
that if i made other people laugh at
someone else
they wouldn't notice what i got going on
and so i could keep them up off me
yup yup yeah yeah it was it was uh see i
probably would have talked about you see
i probably not i'll do it
i was one of them guys that i would just
make people laugh because
it was really because i didn't really
want to do the work some of the work was
hard for me i was like oh
shoot man what y'all doing what hey hey
hey you know i've been messing with
people who
studied that did their homework hey man
come on give me some answers and they'd
be like shut up
i will shut up if you give me the
answers teachers are looking right at
those food
i was one of those and then but i would
make people laugh because they
you know it was easy to do so like i
just started up
they get get the class going so
how old were you or when did you start
doing the eddie murphy and michael
jackson impressions
man eddie murphy from from high school
you know he was the man
for me and uh and michael too as a kid
oh man i remember my play brother up the
street used to dance just like michael
jackson he had the prettiest girlfriend
i said man i want to be like this man
this dude here and i want to dance like
michael like he danced so we always had
dance michael jackson contests and and
we
and he was he brought down eddie
murphy's delirious that he did on hbo
because he had cable before they put the
cable down in the street
while we lived down on the street by the
circle he already had cable and he had a
vcr because he's the only child
we want you know we had to wait you know
so he had all that stuff he brought the
lyrics down and it was over we got cable
right when rocky
three became uh we came out on hbo and
we was like watch rocky three
and delirious all day and we just had a
ball
so what's your go-to uh lines when
you're going to impersonate eddie you're
going to
impersonate mike uh what's your life
what's your go to
well eddie you know i just talk like
like i'll do the laughs
yeah you crazy so what's that what's
that he's a little older now
you talk a little like what's up man how
you doing bro you just talk low and rich
but michael i would go chris what are
you what are you doing chris
what what's chris how are you how are
you but i just talked to he was so cute
when you a lot of people some people
don't like when they get mimic
or they get made so how was it when they
found that you were doing
it and then you saw them for the first
time
oh michael michael loved it because i
heard from his nephews that he was a big
fan
of mine because they showed him the
movies he's uh
they showed him the movies and michael
was uh was loved it man
because he knew everything i did it had
a little bit of michael in it
right he was from friday's i'm dancing
on the porch in the montage doing
michael dance
uh money talks rush hour doing uh the
the karaoke thing
and uh uh even um in
um a death jam i talked about michael
what if michael was a pimp so he knew
that if we had kindred experience or
something and i was a big fan
for sure you said some of your early
influences was
eddie murphy richard pryor who are some
of the other comedians when you were
growing up you like okay
i like his style well definitely bernie
mac
like i said bernie mac was just just
funny naturally funny
um robin harris i didn't get a chance to
meet him but i heard his albums and i
saw him in the movies spike lee movies
and uh different movies like that i just
thought they were
i like naturally funny comedians and uh
and today of course you know uh dave
chappelle
you know a friend of mine people like
that man it's just
just just just make me laugh uh uh
they have to be funny what was it like
performing on the comedy tour in atlanta
because atlanta had used
i don't know if it's still like it like
uh
like this now but atlanta used to have a
bunch of comedy places uptown comedy
store right there on
on peachtree i used to go there all the
time
yeah yeah it's still man there's so many
funny young brothers out there man
you can't even count them on one hand
man on one hand and it's still strong
and they still doing comedy even during
the pandemic man they
they still out there still open
people ain't stopping man so uh yeah man
i can't wait to see who else is out
there but it
we definitely got a good uh track record
of a lot of great comedians coming out
of
atlanta what made you decide to move to
la and not new york to do your comedy
because everybody all the comedians was
coming down to the comedy act theater
and they were uh they were coming from
l.a like d.l
hugley and jamie foxx and all those guys
would come down and they would see me
open up with forum or at times and they
were like man you need to go to la you
you you work you're pretty good you can
get there and i was like okay you really
think so they was like yeah man you need
to go to la
so i knew that la was the place for the
movies and
television and all that stuff and new
york was more theatrical
so that's what made me go out to l.a
so what was it like yo your mom you're
like okay
i'm gonna go i'm been mom and mom dad
i'm gonna i've been to go it alone i've
been
for the deal what were your emotions
like because you know
you know that's not like i got a job
lined up i'm going out there i'm going
to work
you're going to do comedy you got to get
calls you got to get called back
you got gotta get readings there's no
guarantee any of this is going to happen
yeah yeah they were you know my moms and
daddy was so
so supportive but they probably were so
so happy i found something that i need i
was gonna do because they my mother
thought i was gonna live with her
forever
she right because i built a house and i
stay with iraq
she's right but uh she said i just i
just thought you go be with me baby
you know i was just going to help you
out but uh i was fortunate enough man to
to uh
have i knew somebody in l.a now in fact
i moved with my girlfriend from high
school
father lived in l.a so i had a place to
stay my mama felt comfortable about
where i was going because she knew i
wouldn't be out there by myself
so it was just it just was just god man
it worked out so in other words you kept
the girlfriend from high school so you
have a place to stay when you came in
here with a father huh
oh no she was fine i would try to leave
her baby could you just ask your dad
because i didn't think he was going to
agree with him like you crazy gonna be
living up in my house
with my daughter sleeping with my
daughter no but he was cool with it he
was like yeah come on
come on out and it was just things just
fell into place as soon as i graduated
from high school
uh a comedy club opened up comedy act
theater where robin harris and everybody
came from you know
uh and then you know when i was ready to
move to l.a my girlfriend father was
living out there already and uh
i told asked can we go i thought he was
gonna say no and i was gonna have to
get another plan he said yeah it's okay
they kicked me out two months later
but uh i had i had two months to find a
roommate and i was it did i was out i
was on the road rolling in
when i was they were coming home from
work i was just getting up on the couch
because i was out all night on the
comedy club
and they would come home from work and
i'd be like hey getting up off the couch
and
his his wife at the time his new wife
was like he needed to go
he need to go he ain't paying the rent
and he's just sleeping all day
so then i found me a roommate and that's
the rest is history
what are some of the advice that you
would give young and up-and-coming
comedians
trust your you know uh trust your dreams
man go after your dreams
i went out the mine and it all happened
even more than i ever could imagine
happen
uh but uh you know every moment was a
surprise and when a door when a door
closed
another one opens up like i was telling
you i was going for a tv show
i didn't get that but i walked out of
that audition i got fridays
so uh don't get frustrated when the door
closed
just look at find the positive in it and
keep moving
but keep working like marvin gaye said
stay on the floor
and keep dancing because that's the way
somebody's going to see you for the next
part
and when you when you're working even if
it's something small somebody might see
and say oh i got to look for the next
part so you got to just keep doing what
you can do
to to keep going to you know to get to
where you want to go
was death comedy jam the show because i
remember dl ended up
i think dl ended up hosting that and
some of the great comedians have come
through there martin lawrence was the
host for a while
dave chappelle bernie mac steve harvey i
mean so many
yeah what was it what was it like
auditioning being on death comedy jam
did you know a lot of the brothers
and sisters that you were out there
against were going to turn out to be
what they later became
you know i was on the same show as
bernie mac he was the headliner and i
started my the first def jam and i went
up and i thought i
blew the place away i thought that you
know that was nobody gonna follow me
and i went upstairs you know to use the
bathroom i think in new york
wherever we were and i saw a guy up
there and i said hey man you're a
comedian somebody said yo
i said who what's your name i'm burning
him up i said okay you're going up he
said yeah i'm gonna
i said i thought to myself all right
good luck you know because comedian
after me bomb
and then bernie went up there towed the
house down
and i said oh man i got to get back to
work i got to get myself together
but that def jam was my platform that
really got
got me my first agent got me my uh
you know that was the reason why you
know they got me for fridays they saw
you know i was
rising up on depth gm and depth gm tour
and all that stuff so that was my first
big platform
and then fridays were you know was the
um movie stuff
platform give me give me your mount
rushmore comedians
you only get four your four best
comedians of all time
richard pryor robin harris
eddie murphy i gotta say bill cosby
those guys
you left i'm just saying the guys you
left off not that is right or wrong
uh you left off uh chappelle you left
off uh
seinfeld you left off uh lenny bruce you
left off red fox
yeah yeah well those got now red fox is
up there too but he was
way before i could i well i know all
about him because i do comedy and i
studied it
but and chappelle is in my generation so
he's all that
that level with me and he's one of the
greatest don't let me don't don't
be mistaken but ain't none of them gonna
touch richard
ain't none of us gonna ever touch
richard ain't none of us gonna ever
touch robin harris
ain't none of us gonna ever touch eddie
murphy
in movies and stand up and and and bill
cosby
he's one of the greatest richard pryor
used to imitate bill cosby
and and then and then i got to say dick
gregory so it's it's so many man
do you believe that had robin and bernie
live
longer they would have had a greater
place
in the uh uh in the comedic hierarchy
oh for sure robin harris was about to be
out of this world
he would have been like eddie and and
and up there
and probably big just as big as eddie
and bernie
was going it wasn't then he couldn't do
drama comedy he was going he was there
he was already there too because he
stayed here long
so yeah those guys are they on that
mount rushmore for sure man
so when you you write jokes do you just
sit down
i mean so how did it happen i mean so
you know i've talked to
rappers and entertainers and they says
okay if i'm gonna write a song you know
i might be laying down i wake up and i
start writing
or i might be eating and something come
to my head and i just put it down and
start writing
how do you write jokes how long does it
take to take you to write a set
yeah uh it takes it
you know when it comes to me when it
comes to me i usually don't sit down and
think of stuff
i let it come to me and then i'll write
it down or i will get in
uh you know get in a mood or something
and then it just all come to me
and it's like whatever wherever it is uh
wherever i am i'm at or if i go to comic
club that night
some come to me but yeah i write jot
down stuff throughout
you know the year or you know and but
but i just let it come to me because so
much stuff
uh just just comes and then i keep you
know some stuff i let go and some stuff
i keep
was it a difficult transition from go
from stand-up
to acting and is it a natural transition
that a lot of comedians
have gone on to be actors from red fox
to richard pride to eddie murphy
yourself uh bernie mac robin harris i
mean
so many guys uh said the entertainer
bruce i mean so many guys
yeah yeah it's it's a total it's totally
it's totally
different stand up and acting is totally
different
you have to like in stand up you're more
animated and you're more
wired in the movies you got to tone all
that down
and then you got to come up when you
when you need to come down when you need
to
i noticed that when i started doing
acting i said oh man i got to take this
down you know because they got your bit
your head and 100
you know uh close up and you're moving
all around here i'm like i can't do that
here
i gotta calm down right here and look
you know a certain way
so you got to adapt to that and then
also you got to go deeper because you
you plan a part and then you gotta
you know you got you got to go deeper
than uh then uh stand up stand up is you
it's your life and it's hard too at
times but
acting it's another level it's another
level but you're using that act when you
got that comedy tool
and take it to acting it's it's good
have you ever forgotten a line while
you're doing stand-up
oh all the time all time but stand up so
good because you got the audience right
there
and something might happen you might ask
a question and boom
that breaks you to a whole nother thing
and then you go back to whatever you
forgot
and uh you you good again but stand up
ain't nothing like stand up i i love
stan
what are some of the obstacles that you
had to overcome were there doors slammed
in your face
there were the opportunities that you
felt you were deserving of that you
didn't get and you like man
i don't know this might not be for me
because they'd be bulging
you know what that that i've been
blessed man it was like
uh for me uh you know things doors was
just opening
it was just it was just god because like
i said uh def jam
i lost i was in a competition i lost the
competition because i didn't have enough
time for the second round
but the def jam producer ran backstage
and he saw me say man i want you on the
first step
jam you perfect for what we want for dev
jam all you need to do is seven minutes
five minutes
i was like like like when i got fridays
it was like i was sad and i was happy
again
it was like when the door closed another
door open and then uh
when i went to um the comedy club down
here when it first opened i was too
young to get in they had a liquor
license
the manager uh he let me in because i
was just kept
hanging around the front door and then
ricky harris another comedian
he was headlining one weekend and he
said he told the manager
let him in and he wasn't coming in to
work so he was late already so
gary the man he said let him in you
better not drink nothing though but so i
went in
and i didn't drink and uh you know he
didn't see me drink
but i wouldn't make sure that
and you know doors was just open it was
always obstacles
but you know god opened those doors for
me
i'm looking at a house party house party
three in 1994
kid and play teacher camera bernie mac
uh lisa left that lopez wrestler sold
marcus houston eddie griffin
what was that what was that like what
was that set like that that was a great
set man and i was only there for like
two days and that was really my first
movie role when i did that and uh
and um and then at the premiere i told
you that's how i got my agent he came up
to me and said man
you got an agent because he i guess he
saw my little part that i did in uh
house party three
but uh i played a part johnny boos and
then i just uh
i had to do something real quick cause i
only had like a second to make
make the character do something so it
was a it was it was a lot of fun man it
was just uh
you know animated and you know johnny
boo's character and just came up with
something real quick man and uh
uh and it stayed in the movie so it was
good
dead presidents another hood classic
lorenz
how was that oh man so much fun working
with the hughes brothers lorenz tape my
buddy
volcano whitby so many other greats man
it was awesome man
the music they had you know in the movie
and playing around the set
and and you know it was a time a period
piece
uh we had so much fun man and it got me
to show another side of me
serious side uh playing that character
skippy and dead president
is bad so i i was happy to do that
soccer show at the same time i had
fridays out
that year and two in 95 with comedy and
then on the other side i had
you know dead presidents with a serious
side so i was happy to show both sides
of me
did you ever worry about being typecast
not not at that time and uh but i never
worry about it at all because i know
what i could do you know a lot of people
might haven't saw a lot of it yet
uh but i i never worry about it because
i know like uh
once they you know once i do something
different they can play oh okay
i i knew he could do it but i just
wanted to see it like when i did
civilized playbook
that was you know that was a smaller
part but it was it was different more
dramatic and uh then of course the
president but you know that's always on
the back of our minds as you know you
don't want to be
typecast you know get asked your
question no yeah
do typecast actors cash checks that's
right they do
they they do that's right
jim carrey made a lot of money playing
playing the pet detective
that's right he made a lot
he sure did that's right you know you do
what you do best
and you know if you could do something
else that's great but hey
that's all you can do and you're doing
good at it that's okay you mentioned
95 you had the friday the dead president
but 97 might have been one of your best
years
because you have money talk you have
fifth element uh
jackie brown yeah what was 97 like for
you
97 was fun man it was it was do you know
i was producing money talks with charlie
sheen
my own movie and that was another level
uh
and it was great you know being around
great actors like charlie sheen
and paul savino who that was in money
talks that movie
and then uh work with quentin tarantino
and samuel jackson and that jackie brown
that was fun
uh because quentin's great great writer
you know he just whatever the words he
write you could just say
right from the page because it sounds
like you're talking so that was you know
fun and a learning experience
and fifth element was great because i
went to europe with working with luke
for sun one of the greatest
french directors ever and you know out
there man having fun
and on this big set you know playing a
crazy character man that i could go all
the way
you know as far as i want you know in
that character
uh ruby rod you know space character
that was just a gif and i was scared to
do it but once i got in that outfit
and got going i said man this is gonna
be fun and it turned out to be
one of my favorite characters which is
harder um
producing directing the movie acting in
the movie
and which do you like better i like
acting
in a movie and having some a little bit
of say so a little bit of control
uh and that's what mostly you know if
you get an executive producer
uh uh whatever uh you know um
credit you know that because you want to
have a little bit of like so you can
make the movie better
only because you want to participate you
want to uh make
make the project a movie better so i
would say uh
you know the acting is is the hardest
and it's the for me it's the most
rewarding thing to do because that's
what i do
best i think you've been on the set with
a lot of great actors charlie sheen
bruce willis samuel l jackson robert de
niro which one of those guys are those
or any of those who brought out the best
chris chris tucker
i would say man um
i would say charlie sheen because he was
just a nice he's just a nice guy he made
sure i got first credit
i never forget that they you know the
studio wanted him to be first credit at
the time because he was you know a big
star
right now he said no you brought this
project you should be uh
your name should be first you you should
be the man you should be up front
so i was i never forgot that young kid
somebody like on his level
uh so you know telling the studio no
this is his movie i'm just starting i'm
you put me second credit
so i always remember charlie for that
and then of course
uh you know uh jackie chan you know just
having fun with him and
and growing up watching his movies too
and and i knew i could
be man uh be funny and be physical and
all that stuff in rush hour so
i knew that was a great um uh vehicle
for me man to show
show my um talents i've had some rappers
on here and they say when they collab or
someone has them on a feature
they trying to kill it yeah i know this
is your album this is your song
but i'm trying to kill you on your own
song when you're in a movie or you're in
a scene
with an actor are you trying to like
yeah i notice your movie
but they're gonna remember me you know
what
no i cuz i i gotta get feed i gotta get
feedback
for people like like when i was in money
talks and um
what's his name savino paul savina
working with a great actor like that
the key is working with other great
actors because they're going to give you
some stuff
and it's going to bring the best out of
you you know
you know great actor uh we if you're
working with great actors bet they gonna
bring it out of you and you're gonna be
like
whoa and you'll be in the moment more
and acting is a little different
because this is teamwork you know like
football team it's teamwork you wanna we
wanna work with the best
and the best directors rush hour
why and did you know it was going to be
what they became uh
no it was the same thing when i did
fridays i did the first rush hour
i never wanted to do a neck another one
because that was just like
i never even thought like that i was
like just do a great job with this one
and move on and do another great job for
another movie
uh but you know like i said they all i
didn't have nothing on the table at the
time and they offered me another one for
the rush hour too
and uh then i said all right i'll just
do it i don't have nothing
at that time and we did it and we had
fun with that one
and uh with the the third one uh you
know same thing
that happened but no i didn't know it
was going to be franchi a franchise
and i appreciate it and i'm glad that it
had enough legs to to go you know last
at
last like that but uh yeah i didn't know
so because that was really like the
first time you like you could be
you you could still be funny but you had
a
more of a drama you was actually like a
detective you're like james carter was
actually trying to catch somebody
yeah yeah and that was like a movie that
i grew up watching eddie murphy beverly
hills cop
48 hours so little things that i always
dreamed of like man i got to get to
that level you know one day you know
like like like my heroes
childhood heroes richard pryor and his
movies and stuff
so yeah what type of physical shape do
you need to be in to do those type of
movies did you do any of your own stunts
do you like doing your own stunts
i did all of my stunts in the first rush
hour i made sure i got in shape because
i knew that
you know jackie chan did his own stunts
by watching you know researching him and
and watching that you know him saying i
do my own stunts so i made sure i got in
shape
and for the second one i made sure i got
even more better shape
because work you know action movies it's
a lot
it's a lot it's a lot you go on a set
you might be there all day
because they're gonna need you to fall
or jump off something and this that that
so it takes action movies you need to be
in shape and you're working in the
middle of the night
sometimes uh early in the morning so you
want to be healthy
enough to be able to have that the
energy that you you know come across on
the screen
and physical uh stuff you need to uh do
you know to make the scene work
how did you get paired with jackie chan
and rush hour and i read what jackie
chan says like when he first met you he
wasn't so sure about you oh
yeah cause it was it was uh well i was
doing movies with new line cinema and
jackie i think they bought a lot of his
movies uh
new line bought a lot of his movies that
he did overseas in you know in china in
hong kong
and they had a relationship with him and
then they had relationship from fridays
and money talks with me
and we me and my manager at the time he
was looking for something bigger and
seeing what the studio had and they said
well
uh we want to partner up with somebody
else they said we got jackie chan's got
a project
but somebody they're looking at somebody
else i think it was wesley snipes martin
lawrence and
a few other people and they said they're
looking at other people but
maybe maybe you know he might it might
work so
we uh went after it tried to get this
script the rush hour script and and do
the movie with jackie
and uh it came together uh because uh
the one of the producers
wanted me in the movie they wanted
somebody a fresh face just like in
fridays they wanted a fresh face
somebody who wasn't already established
uh and i got the role i got the part
with uh rush hour because we had a
history with new line
and jackie was working with them and
they put us together
so that's how that happened did you know
the magic
that you guys would create did you know
it would be this
when you two guys got together i felt it
because
i was comfortable i was comfortable
around jackie because he was humble
you know he still is great great guy
great man
and uh of course i you know he he was a
a a hero of mine because you know jack
chance is cool
but uh i knew that i could say whatever
i want to say around him and
we we had good chemistry and from the
start
you know uh and he was in a and so i
think out of that
you know great things happen in 2006 you
negotiated contract
25 million dollars for rush hour you the
first i think if i'm not mistaking the
cred
to crack that threshold
did did it add pressure on being the
highest paid actor at the time
in entertainment what what was going
through your mind here's a
black kid from atlanta georgia
former stand-up and now i'm the highest
paid
i didn't go to juilliard i didn't go to
one of these prominent acting schools
and go to yale or this or that
but here it is a black a black kid from
atlanta a black man now
and i'm the highest paid in the world
yeah you know i didn't think of it man i
was so you know i was so like back then
i said
after the success of the first rush hour
i said well my movie made over 100 some
million dollars tom cruise movie made
over 100 something
he's getting 20 million i said i need to
get 20 million so i just went in there
and
told the studio i said well you know if
y'all want to do another one
i want 20 million and they said okay hey
because they knew that it was gonna make
a whole bunch of money
and i and i and i um i felt like i was
worth that
because i knew this i knew the movie was
gonna make some more money too and i
just was
i guess that's the business side of me
that said
go ahead and ask for it this is time to
ask for it and [__]
do you wish you were throwing out a high
number
[Laughter]
no no because uh it worked out
it worked out uh
did eddie murphy turn this movie down no
eddie was never attached to uh rush
hours you know
it was on i think martin was a con it
was they was considering martin
and wesley but uh yeah that was the only
thing i heard but eddie i don't think he
was ever
involved you've also been had a lot of
uh
cameos and music videos yeah
i mean anybody that's ever been around
you until it's hard not to like you
you're an easy person to like
because you're like you're exactly what
people would think you would be i mean
when they see you and they see you in
those movies and they're like i wonder
how you
and when people ask me say man you know
i was like yeah i know i know chris
talking
what's he like what you see on tv he's
exactly like that
i'm talking about nothing different he
he's fun
he's that make you laugh he's exactly
what you thi
whatever you thinking that's what he is
thank you man thank you
i try to be man no i don't and that
that's all you can be
you know just be you yeah as i mentioned
you you have a lot you like in tupac
california love dr dre keep the heads
ringing
mace and uh did it feel so good what is
it about the
why they keep why they keep shouting you
are having you in in their video
yo i guess it's the culture man because
they know i love music and hip hop
r b you like people have you and
everybody video you dancing to everybody
video you like me
hey i've been in the video if he did it
i like music man i like i like
you know uh country i like gospel i like
everything man
so it's just part of me and that's part
of part of my my spirit man
you know put i put music on and have fun
dance and laugh
and that keeps me happy uh so it's a
part of me and then
you know and the movies and the
soundtracks come together and you know
with
keep your head ringing with dr dre that
was on fridays uh
michael jackson we were friends and he i
got into rock my world video which you
know was a blessing you know uh because
michael don't put everybody in the
videos only
chosen to be in his videos and i was and
i every time that song come on i got
great memories to come back
you know on that it seems like comedians
are getting discovered a different way
now because now since the advent of
social media
we see a lot of guys on ig you know
doing little stuff doing skits and maybe
they're doing tick tock or they're doing
ig live
yeah are there some some comedians up
and coming comedians that you look like
okay
your young brother this young this young
female has a chance
you know what i i need to get on more
and and see who's out there because
there's a lot of talented people
out there man and one kid i think you
mentioned one kid
imitates me on tick-tock man i think
that that kid's just talented man
uh but uh and he's gonna go far
uh but it's it's uh definitely a new uh
platform like we had def jam
and they got into the movies this is a
platform that's getting a lot of people
uh going to the next level you know uh
like justin
uh beaver got discovered uh doing
something on um
on social media and then drake and what
he did a little tv too but
that's a new platform that's a new
format so that's what yeah you uh
the old comedians had def jam had comic
view
comic lost a lot of careers so so what
what's the new media what's the new
what's the new
uh avenue for comedians
to be what's the next depth jam what's
the next comic view
um i think it's going to continue to be
uh something like tick tock
and social media man and all that stuff
twitter and all that
it's going to continue to be that for a
while and people are going to
be discovered off of that and then go
into uh you know of course
uh screaming uh you know on all those
you know platforms like that netflix and
uh
prime amazon prime and hbo max and
they're gonna get be selling shows and
they're going to be buying them up
man because it's just uh it's just wide
open right now
which is good you know as you mentioned
earlier uh
the the pandemic has been a blessing and
a curse because now you're getting guys
doing
netflix features for uh uh for comedy
and they're getting a boatload of money
you just perform right there
and and everything's taken care of and
they just run it
yeah yeah it's a blessing man because uh
you know
back in the day it was only hbo or show
time now you got you got so many
different places you could take uh
a comedy uh special uh a show or
something like that
and so it's it's wide open if you got
the talent
and you're willing to do the work you
you know you could get out there
and make it in this business for sure
how have you been
you look at dave chappelle and he had it
all he was on comedy central he was
doing the sketch comedy
and he was at the apex and he walked all
he walked away from it
and then gradually he took steps and he
built it back up and now he's back
you know a lot of people believe that
he's he right now he's the gold standard
when it comes to
uh comedians how has his resurgence
reinvigorated you i mean yeah cause you
know he did the right thing
he was uncomfortable with something and
he wanted his freedom
uh to express himself in his art and he
did the right thing and it and it helped
him
come back to where he is today and um
and he everything that he left on the
table he got that
and and double and more you know uh and
we kind of got like some of the similar
uh walk you know i
kind of took long breaks and got my you
know and lived my life and
uh you know got you know traveled all
over the world and grew up
and uh you know and you know toured and
been touring and stuff but
and and ready to do more you know movies
and all types of stuff
i'm still young and can do that thank
god and um
so we kind of got the same kind of walk
and we we we uh
encourage each other in that in that in
an aspect aspect
and uh man you got to have time you got
to grow and i think i truly believe
art good art comes from your real life
experiences and you don't have
that balance and real life experiences
like when we grew when i grew up that
was all
the friday stuff that was all the dev
jam stuff now
the stuff that i'll do from this point
on is where i've been
you know these last 20 years you know
growing up i think
if they were to remake friday and cube
said they might
they're thinking about it he says
they're writing it right now
would you want to come back in it and
would you want to come back as smoky
you know what i i you know it's people
some people say do it
some people say don't but for me
personally
i probably won't because i never i never
want to shortchange my audience and my
fans
because you know they i know they want
it because that's what they know and
they love it and i'm glad they love it
but i don't want to come back in
something that that i probably uh
can't do what they ex what they want you
know
uh me to do because i've you know i've
grown
uh and not not only grown i'm different
right right that's a that was a 25 that
was a 23
24 year old chris tucker this is a whole
different chris tucker it's a whole
nother chris tucker and you know you
don't want to shortchange
uh your fans for money and uh you know
you don't try to
and that's one thing i think and it's
best to keep that one you know because i
can't do what i did
uh when i watch fridays now i'm like i
can't i can't do that i was where i was
and i was acting but now i'm in my 40s
now
uh i could do something even better
because uh if you like that character
imagine what i'm gonna do uh in the
future
you're from atlanta as i mentioned the
sports team
in atlanta haven't had the greatest
success we got the falcons we got the
braves
uh uh hank aaron
hey gary we're going to talk about as a
matter of fact let's talk about hank we
just lost hank early this morning i
think he was 86 years of age
at lamin icon when you think about
legends of atlanta you think about
obviously dr king
you think about uh hank aaron you think
about andrew young
maynard jackson some some of the greats
and now
20 years from now we're going to be
thinking about uh keshia bottoms and
we're going to think about our great
mayor
uh abrams
and keisha volumes is the mayor right
now torsion brown
but talk about hey cause i know you had
a personal relationship with mr aaron
oh man i've been blessed man to meet so
many great
legends and we stand on the shoulders of
so many greats man in in my
profession uh and in others man and i
met i've
had it because i'm from atlanta i had a
chance to meet mrs aaron
several times and you know and i was
surprised he knew my name you know first
like him people like him and bill
russell and jim brown and uh
bill withers i you know i hung out with
all these people because uh
god blessed me to be in the in that
circle in their world
but you know i i did his party last year
his birthday party
his wife miss aaron invited me to go up
and say some words man and i just
i just get a kick out of being around
him people like ambassador young
and you know i called him on martin
luther king weekend but
he was such a down-to-earth legend an
icon
iconic person but he was so humble and
that's what i would always remember he
was a hey chris
i'm like that's hank aaron he said my
name you know and
some people get me like that and he's
one of them
that he's just humble he he shows you
that he cares and he don't wear this
i'm hank aaron on my shoulder like a lot
of people we know do
and he never did that with me and always
always just gave me that
uh reinsurance like you're gonna be all
right keep moving young man
another atlanta icon we lost earlier
also john lewis
you you can't have a mount rushmore of
legends in atlanta without putting john
lewis on that
on that plaque yeah man i call i called
him also on uh you know
a couple of weeks before he passed i you
know i was praying and i got up and
someone called you
and i got him on the phone i was so
surprised i thought i was gonna leave a
message
and he said uh yes and i think i was
just thanking him thanking him for
everything he's done like i called him
bouncing young and he's just
oh no thank you young man thank you and
i was and i thank god i was able to talk
to him before he passed
uh you that [__] you that kobe's final
game
yeah obviously you know kobe 20 years
he wasn't what he once was but did you
even in your wildest imagination
envisioned
that kobe would go out in his last game
and drop
60. never man that dude was great for
real
he was great for real and you know he's
he would go down like the legends bruce
lee and so many great stats just mystery
around
their work ethic and and things they did
to prepare to be great
and uh i never thought that uh yeah he
would stole that many points but he just
showed
you know he had that anointing man and
uh he was one of the greatest
you like basketball i see you at the
all-star game a couple of times
construct give me your give me your
starting five if you can build a team
starting five any player past and
present
who's your starting five well bill
russell
because he know my name uh michael
jordan okay
uh kobe magic and
uh kareem you know what
hold up how you gonna lead gold james
off the list you got all these
you got you ain't putting lebron
oh man forget you know what that's my
boy too okay put lebron's on that he's
coming in for the guys he's
[Laughter]
if you could do it all over again what
what would you change what would chris
tucker change about anything
maybe you changed nothing but if you
could change something or you wanted to
change something what would chris tucker
change
about his career to date i wouldn't
change anything
that comes to mind but i tell you what
you know any mistakes
that you make or i might have made their
learning experiences so you don't want
to change learning experiences
right you got to make sure you learn
quick and don't
keep making the same mistakes uh and so
i don't i wouldn't change anything and
i would uh you know take i would i pray
that i never forget
the mistakes that i might have made and
and learn from them and keep moving
huh we're gonna rap with this one talk
yes sir if
how do i say this
your career has been
you know you you said you know you took
you you've been like chapelle
chappelle walked away you walked away
you came back
what are we gonna see from tuck in the
next 10 years
are you going to do more acting you're
going to be more behind the camera
what is what what should we expect from
chris tucker
from today moving forward i
you know what a lot of good things man i
want to do it all you know i want to do
it all you know of course more acting
more more of a more whatever whatever
whatever god's
wherever god guides him to be honest
with you and then i want to say the time
i took off
was so important and i see the fruits of
that now
like i could you know like i told you i
called congressman john lewis because i
was around him and i
and i and i became uh and i know i knew
him because i was available to go
down to the pederman bridge the edmund
petterman bridge
uh when he invited me and you know bill
you know bill withers hang out with uh
with uh bill willis and um and my and my
buddy who
used to take pictures uh for muhammad
ali i'm gonna think of his name
brown oh no not bonnie deeney
ambassador young and you know i thank
god that he
allowed me to step back so i could be
calm so i can know them and be friends
with them
and and now you know hopefully they stay
down around forever but i was able
i'm able to say i knew them that they
they
uh gave me good advice and and and stuff
like that i would have never
known these people if i was just good
straight on my career just worried about
me
so i can always have that wisdom to go
forward
uh sidney poitier going to lunch with
him and harry belafonte
these guys knowing these guys and
spending that time so
those things you can't you you can't
imagine it unless you you willing to
say oh you know i'm gonna leave that i'm
gonna step back for a minute let me
let me grow as a man and as a person and
travel the world and stuff
i would have never experienced those
things if i wouldn't have faith
and faith in god and those things could
never be taken away from me
and i still got you know a great career
you know coming you know ahead of me
but just to say to say that uh
i want to do it all and i'm able to do
it to produce direct and
and write and find discover other great
actors comedians uh um you know
on along along the way so yeah i want to
do it all and i'm looking forward to
doing it all
you know uh uh wherever god takes
got to get your super bowl pick who you
got getting to and who's winning the
super bowl
well i'm gonna tell you my boy brady i
love brady yeah i met brady at michael
jordan's golf tournament
and i thought he was black at first
because somebody said just like you say
what's up tuck
somebody said what's up tuck i said well
who this brother is i turn around
it's tom brady and ever since then i
love tom brady i say oh that's my dog
for life right here
because he's just down so i'm going with
tom on
on that and i love aaron i never met
aaron uh rogers so
i'm going with tom all the way on that
you guys keeps i'm going with i'm going
with my boy the chiefs and um
my homeboy i'm home i'm
i'm going home i had a chance to meet
him at the all-star game man i
i slipped on that one i don't miss stuff
like that he was sitting across the way
and i didn't get in the end of the
all-star of chicago i didn't get a
chance to shake his hand but
i'm going with him i know he felt felt
my spirit
and uh i'm going with him the chiefs are
uh uh
and brady cheats and brady's in the
super bowl and i'm not gonna call them
because both of them are my boys so i'm
gonna see what happens let destiny take
his course
let history nba who wins the
championship this year
nets lakers clippers
celtics sixes but the clippers
have a a a they have a vendetta
they have uh they gotta win this year so
i think the clip is gonna be there
fighting like cats cats and dogs
with my boy lou uh hitting them up and
uh
and my boy doc downing but you know they
got this they got a special menu coming
at the place though on foresight you
know they got a special meeting of
little pepper wings
chicken chips this chicken will be
fighting that that place
where is that at where is that you don't
eat that magic
oh yes sir yes sir baby swinging
man tucker i appreciate it bro i
appreciate the time today dad
love you man thank you bro this is
awesome all my life
sacrifice hustle pay the price wanna
slice
got the bowl of dice that's why all my
life i've been grinding all my life look
all my life been running all my life
sacrifice
plus will pay the price wanna slice got
to roll it dice that's why
all my life i've been grinding all my
life
you know what to do hit the subscribe
button to become an official member of
club shayshay
where we always do something before
tucson